现在我们来试试 Podman 吧
So let's try Podman now.
我们要从 Buildah 搬到波德曼
We're gonna move on from
Buildah into Podman.
下面是下一节
Which is the next section here.
所以现在我想运行这个容器，我想让它把 3000 口暴露在我
So now I want to run this container and
I want it to expose port 3000 just like I
正在执行 Docker run 节点 Web Service，对吗 ?
was doing Docker run node web service,
right?
在这里，你会发现这个容器上也安装了 podman 。
So here, you'll notice that podman is also
installed on this particular container.
但如果你需要安装它，我就会给你说明如何做到这一点。
But if you need to install it, I left you
instructions on how to do that as well.
所以我要做的就是我要说波德曼跑了
So what I'm going to do here is
I'm going to say podman run,
这个你要给它群经理吧
this one you have to give
it a cgroup manager, right?
对于控制组，因为缺省情况下不一定有控制组。
For the control groups because it
doesn't necessarily have one by default.
Docker 是这样做的
Whereas Docker does, so
我要说 cgroup-manager ， cgroupfs。
I'm gonna say cgroup-manager, cgroupfs.
然后我要告诉它 -p 3000:3000，它将为我们展示这个港口。
And then I'm gonna tell it -p 3000:3000,
which is going to expose that port for us.
然后我要告诉它看看 localhost/my-app-buildah。
And then I'm gonna tell it to
look on localhost/my-app-buildah.
要不我不告诉它本地的主机它就出去试试
Otherwise if I don't tell it the local
host part, it's gonna go out and try and
在 Docker Hub 上查找或类似的内容。
find on Docker Hub or something like that.
好吧那波德曼会为我们做这个容器
Okay and then this will have Podman
execute this container for us.
然后你就可以了
And there you go.
您可以看到这一情况现在正在运行。
You can see that this is now running.
如果我点击这里，打开链接就可以了。
If I click here,
Open Link And there you go.
这将在该 Buildah 容器内运行我们的节点服务，
This is running our node service
inside of that Buildah container,
我暴露了这个港口
which I exposed that port.
然后波德曼就是那个在 Docker 里执行的容器
And then Podman is actually the one
executing that container within the Docker
容器。
container.
我知道这事有很多层面的，对吧 ?
I recognize that there's a lot
of levels to this, right?
这就是野兽的本性抱歉
Which is kind of the nature of the beast,
sorry.
我没告诉你 Buildah 和 Podman 比 Docker 好
I'm not telling you that Buildah and
Podman are any better than Docker.
我不告诉你 Docker 比 Buildah 和 Podman 好
I'm not telling you that Docker is
any better than Buildah and Podman.
有各种不同的用例，其中一个可能更适用于您。
There are various different use cases
where one might be better for you.
请记住，不仅仅是 Buildah ， Podman 和 Docker。
And keep in mind that there's more than
just Buildah and Podman and Docker.
还有像火箭一样的东西
There's also things like Rocket, right,
火箭是另一个类似的
Rocket's another one
that does similar things.
它来自 CoreOS ，效果很好。
And it's from CoreOS and
it works really well.
有一堆不同引擎的容器
There's a bunch of different engines for
containers.
如果你要开始的话我猜你是
If you're just getting starting out,
which I'm guessing you are,
如果你在看这个课程我会建议把它贴在 Docker上
if you're watching this course,
I'd recommend sticking to Docker.
Docker 的美好之处在于它已经存在
The nice thing about Docker
is it's been around for so
有那么多人使用它你可以用谷歌
long and there's so many people
using it that you can Google for
任何事情都会发生在网上
anything and
it's going to be on the Internet.
别人会有你的问题就能解决的对吧
Someone else is going to have your problem
and it's gonna be able to be fixed, right?
虽然 Buildah 和 Podman有一个，但它们还是很新的。
Whereas Buildah and Podman,
one, they're still quite new.
所以他们还在改变很多
So they're still changing a lot.
没有那么多文件来支持它。
And there's just not as much
documentation out there for it.
所以当你选择的时候记住这一点
So keep that in mind when you're choosing.
所以其他一些很酷的东西，我认为是很酷的。
So something else that's pretty cool,
that I think is pretty cool.
实际上可以使用 Buildah ，就像
You can actually use Buildah,
so just pretend for
第二个我在 Linux 电脑上，或者我在 WSL 或者类似的地方。
a second that I was on a Linux computer or
I was here in WSL or something like that.
实际上，我可以将 Buildah 推送到我的本地 Docker 注册表。
I can actually have Buildah push into
my Docker registry, my local one.
然后，我可以使用 Docker 来执行 Buildah 容器，
And then I can use Docker to
execute the Buildah container which
真的很酷
is really cool too.
所以，这些事情在我们的共同努力下是非常好的。
So again, those things work really
well together side by side.
所以我就把指挥留在那里了
So I actually left the command in there.
如果你和 Linux 合作，我会在这里展示给你们看。
If you're working with Linux,
and I'll show you here.
在波德曼这里
Down here in Podman.
所以如果你这样做了，在同一层面上就有 Docker ，对，
So if you ran this and
you had Docker on the same level, right,
这在我的 Mac OS 上是不行的因为它在一个容器里
this wouldn't work in my Mac OS one right
now because it's within a container.
所以它实际上看不到 Docker。
So it actually can't see Docker.
如果我说 buildah push localhost/my-app-buildah
If I say buildah push
localhost/my-app-buildah
docker-daemon-my-app-buildah:latest 。
docker-daemon-my-app-buildah:latest.
这实际上会将它推送到我的 Docker 容器中。
This would actually push it
into my Docker container.
我想你需要做的就是
I think what you need to do is you need to
在容器中显示 Docker 守护程序。
expose the Docker daemon
inside of the container.
所以我要退出了
So I'm gonna exit out of this.
我们要把这个变得更复杂
We've gotta make this
even more complicated.
我们会说
We're gonna say
-v /var/run/docker.sock
:/var/run/docker.sock。
:/var/run/docker.sock.
好了现在我应该可以过来说
Okay, now I should be able
to come here and say,
回到 Buildah 的时候我把它的所有注册表都杀了
Back here in Buildah cuz I killed
all the the registry that it had.
所以我要重建这个内置的容器。
So I have to rebuild
the buildah container.
所以我要说的是 buildah， bud -f ./Dockerfile
So I'm gonna say buildah,
bud -f ./Dockerfile
我在哪儿
Where am I?
我必须在一个消息来源的内部
I have to be inside of a source.
好的， buildah bud -f
Okay, buildah bud -f
./Dockerfile -t
我的应用程序 - buildah...
my-app-buildah..
好吧那就建
Okay, that'll build
我的 Docker 容器。
my Docker container.
现在，我意识到我给了它一个体积。
And now, I actually realize
that I gave it a volume.
所以它确实在运行之间保持了这种关系。
So it actually did keep this between runs.
但尽管如此，一切都应该起作用。
But nonetheless, okay,
that should all work.
这都是储存的
That's all stored.
然后就在这里，如果我说， buildah push，就应该工作了，
And then here,
it should work if I say, buildah push,
好的我们可以把它推给一个注册中心
right, cuz we can push
it out to a registry.
Localhost/my-app-buildah ，因此
Localhost/my-app-buildah, so
我在推那个集装箱
I'm pushing that container.
我们要把它推到
And we're going to push it to
docker-dae:my app-buildah:latest 。
the docker-dae:my app-buildah:latest.
所以现在我打开了那个连接
So now because I opened that connection,
在 Docker 主机和容器之间进行绑定安装。
that bind mount between my Docker host and
into the container.
现在 Buildah 可以从集装箱里
Now Buildah can actually
push out of the container
Docker 桌面的本地 Docker 注册表运行。
into my local Docker registry
of Docker desktop running.
然后我就能执行这个内置容器
And then I'm going to be able to
execute this buildah container
在 Docker的主机内部。
outside of the inside of
the host with Docker.
所以你在这里看到的是它在复制容器
So what you see here this is
actually it copying the container,
在容器外和 Docker中使用。
out of the container and into Docker.
这不可能是网络，对，就在我的容器里。
This isn't going to the network, right,
this is just staying within my container.
所以现在我该说，码头跑了，注意了
So now I should be able to say,
docker run, and notice
就在我的 MAC里面，对，我现在不在集装箱里面。
this is just inside of my MAC, right,
I'm not inside of the container now.
- it - app-buildah
-it my-app-buildah
巴什和你走
bash and here you go.
我现在正在运行我使用 Buildah 构建的 Docker 容器
I am now inside of the container running
Docker that I built with Buildah
还有同样的事
and same thing here.
如果我说我的 app - app -buildah 和
If I say my-app-buildah and
我说 -p 3000:3000。
I say -p 3000:3000.
这应该执行我的节点。
This should execute my node.
这事已经有点不对劲了
Something's already bound on that.
所以还是说 3001吧。
So let's just say 3001.
所以现在我来这里说当地的主机 3001。
So now if I come over here and
say local host 3001.
现在，我实际上正在运行我使用 Buildah 工具链构建的节点服务器，
Now I'm actually running the node server
that I built with the Buildah tool chain,
但我要用 Docker 来完成它
but I'm using Docker to do it.
因此，这证明了 Buildah 不构建 Docker 的观点
So this is kind of proving my point
that Buildah does not build Docker
容器内置 OCI 容器，对吗 ?
containers it builts OCI containers,
right?
但两者都是交替工作的。
But they both work interchangeably.
我可以构建 Docker 容器。
And I could build a Docker container.
我也可以用波德曼来执行
And I could use Podman
to execute that as well.
所以这很酷
So that's pretty cool.
我没想到会这么做
I did not expect that to work.
我要重新强调一个人可能会问的问题
I'm gonna re-emphasize the point
that someone might ask,
我为什么要立即在 Docker 上使用 Buildah 和 Podman ?
why would I use Buildah and
Podman over a Docker right now?
我认为最真正的原因是不使用 Docker。
And I think the real strongest
reason is to not use Docker.
一些人可能对他们为什么不想使用 Docker表示强烈的意见。
And some people might have strong opinions
of why they would not wanna use Docker.
我不知道他们是什么
I don't necessarily know what they are.
但它确实鼓励良性竞争使用其中一些竞争对手，
But it does encourage healthy competition
to use some of these competitors and
而不是被锁定在一个生态系统里
not be locked into one ecosystem.
所以，不是我觉得 Docker 是坏人，我觉得其实是在做
So,not that I think Docker are bad people,
I think actually they're doing really
他们都是社会的好成员
great things and
they're good members of the community so.